{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1)Amount of fluid that leaks from a higher-pressure discharge to a lower pressure discharge is called?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Air",
        "b": "Oil",
        "c": "Slip",
        "d": "Enthalpy"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2)Slip in a pump depends on which of following parameters?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Pressure",
        "b": "Wear",
        "c": "Temperature gradient",
        "d": "Heat flux"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3)If slip exceeds 5 percent, the pumps needs to be ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Dragged",
        "b": "Intermittent",
        "c": "Serviced",
        "d": "Dumped"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4)Maximum efficiency of reciprocating pump is ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Upto 50%",
        "b": "Upto 600%",
        "c": "Upto 70%",
        "d": "Upto 85%"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5)For a good condition, slip should be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Below 2 percent",
        "b": "2 to 4 percent",
        "c": "Above 5 percent",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6)Reciprocating pumps has ____ efficiency compared to centrifugal pumps",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Equal",
        "b": "Exponential",
        "c": "Higher",
        "d": "Lower"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7)Which of the following are the beneficial effects of air vessel fitted to the delivery side of a reciprocating pump ? <br> 1: Ensuring Constant rate of discharge <br> 2: Reduction in power consumption <br> 3: Increase in discharge",
        "answers": {
        "a": "1 and 2",
        "b": "2 and 3",
        "c": "All of the above",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8)The ……………………….. of a double acting reciprocating pump as compared to the single acting pump will almost be double.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Weight",
        "b": "flow output",
        "c": "head",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9)The work saved by fitting an air vessel to a single acting reciprocating pump is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "30%",
        "b": "55%",
        "c": "72%",
        "d": "85%"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10)The discharge of a double acting reciprocating pump is (where L = Length of stroke, A = Cross-sectional area of piston and N = Speed of crank in RPM)",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2LAN/60",
        "b": "LAN/60",
        "c": "LAN",
        "d": "2LAN"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
